<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>io.github.ladaapp.lada</id>

    <name>Lada</name>
    <summary>Recover pixelated adult videos</summary>

    <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
    <project_license>AGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
    
    <branding>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#9141ac</color>
        <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#3d3846</color>
    </branding>

    <developer id="io.github.ladaapp">
        <name>ladaapp</name>
    </developer>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="sex-themes">intense</content_attribute>
    </content_rating>

    <categories>
        <category>Video</category>
    </categories>

    <description>
        <p>Lada is a tool designed to recover pixelated adult videos (JAV). It helps restore the visual quality of such content, making it more enjoyable to watch:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Recover Pixelated Videos: Restore pixelated or mosaic scenes in adult videos.</li>
            <li>Watch/Export Videos: Use either the CLI or GUI to watch or export your restored videos.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>The process is pretty resource-intensive and this Flatpak package will not run on all hardware. Please read the README file of the project on GitHub.</p>
    </description>

    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/ladaapp/lada</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/ladaapp/lada/issues</url>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.ladaapp.lada.desktop</launchable>

    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://github.com/ladaapp/lada/raw/main/assets/screenshot_gui_1_dark.png</image>
            <caption>Watching restored video</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://github.com/ladaapp/lada/raw/main/assets/screenshot_gui_2_dark.png</image>
            <caption>Exporting restored video</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://github.com/ladaapp/lada/raw/main/assets/screenshot_cli_1.png</image>
            <caption>Exporting restored video via CLI</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release date="2025-10-06" version="0.8.1">
            <description>
                <p>This Release is mostly about packaging improvements as this marks the first release for Windows.</p>
                <p>Changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>GUI: Drop files onto Export View or use Add button to add to restore queue</li>
                    <li>GUI: Drop files onto Watch View or use Open button to play them</li>
                    <li>packaging: Lada is now packaged for Windows</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-10-02" version="0.8.0">
            <description>
                <p>Revamped the GUI so it can be used with multiple files enabling you to queue a batch of files for restoration. You can choose if you want the start the app in watch mode (watch restored video in realtime) or in export mode (restore one or multiple files in the background to watch later)</p>
                <p>Similarly, the CLI now also accepts multiple files by passing a directory of files as input.</p>
                <p>Other changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>GUI: Toggle fullscreen mode by double-clicking the video</li>
                    <li>GUI/CLI: Set file name pattern used to determine file names of output file(s)</li>
                    <li>GUI: Fix occasional glitch in fullscreen mode where screen became full black (or white on light theme)</li>
                    <li>GUI: Set custom FFmpeg encoder options. Previously this was only available in CLI</li>
                    <li>GUI: New setting to choose a default output directory. Use it if you don't want to see the File/Folder dialog when clicking Restore</li>
                    <li>GUI: Fixed crash when opening files containing audio with samplerate other than 48 kHz. This probably only affected Windows users</li>
                    <li>CLI: Removed --preserve-relative-scale. --output now is optional. Added --list-devices</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-07-04" version="0.7.2">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Turns out the new "accurate" model introduced in v0.7.1 wasn't as accurate as I hoped. The "fast" model is now the default model, if you need something more accurate try detection model v2 or v3.1-accurate. V2 probably works better in most scenarios.</li>
                    <li>GUI: Added fullscreen option for Restoration Preview</li>
                    <li>GUI: Added option to switch color scheme. System ist default (as it has been) but you can also explicitly set dark or light mode if you want or the system detection doesn't work</li>
                    <li>Packaging:You can now use Nvidia hardware-accelerated video encoders also in Docker and Flatpak builds</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-06-24" version="0.7.1">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Updated mosaic detections models: "fast" and "accurate". "Fast" is pretty much the same model that was shipped in v0.7.0, the new and larger "accurate" model is somewhat slower but catches mosaics which the fast one doesn't detect (new default model).</li>
                    <li>Detection model can now also be selected in the GUI sidebar</li>
                    <li>Additional CLI options: --list-mosaic-detection-models, --list-mosaic-restoration-models</li>
                    <li>Fix GUI becoming unresponsive when models are loaded for the first time (opening a file)</li>
                    <li>Added build instructions for Windows</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-03-31" version="0.7.0">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>New mosaic detection model: Much faster and more accurate</li>
                    <li>Additional CLI options for video encoding settings: --custom-encoder-options, --list-codecs and --preset</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-02-07" version="0.6.0">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Mosaic restoration: Removes mosaics more consistently, especially on lower-quality videos</li>
                    <li>Mosaic restoration: Slightly fewer artifacts on certain scenes due to training on a bigger dataset</li>
                    <li>CLI: create output directory if it doesn't exist instead of crashing</li>
                    <li>Removed bj-pov finetuned restoration model, no improvement compared to new generic model</li>
                    <li>Mosaic restoration dataset creation script: more accuracy for the NSFW detection model</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2025-01-24" version="0.5.0">
            <description>
                <p>The only user-visible change this time is the inclusion of DeepMosaics pretrained restoration model.</p>
                <p>Otherwise, focused on improvements of dataset creation and reducing dependencies to make it easier to build and train new or enhance the existing mosaic restoration model.</p>
                <p>Lada is now also available as a docker image on DockerHub (CLI only)</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-20" version="0.4.2">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>GUI: keep current playhead position after toggling preview or doing config adjustments</li>
                    <li>GUI: fix preview/passthrough keyboard shortcut not working</li>
                    <li>GUI: attempt to fix stuck playback after seeking very long files</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-18" version="0.4.1">
            <description>
                <p>Fixes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>GUI: Fix occasional freeze when app gets closed</li>
                    <li>GUI: Fix occasional freeze when seeking a video</li>
                    <li>GUI: Fix audio/video getting out-of-sync</li>
                    <li>Clean up temporary file after hitting an error or program is closed while export is running</li>
                    <li>Fix always limiting queue sizes to 1 when setting up restoration pipeline</li>
                    <li>GUI: Fix broken Passthrough (disabled preview) mode</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>GUI: Pause video if export button is clicked to select a file destination</li>
                    <li>Support files where video stream has an offset to its audio stream</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-15" version="0.4.0">
            <description>
                <p>Huge speed boost on high-performant hardware:</p>
                <p>Parts of the restoration pipeline are now being run in parallel with buffering in between each step. This enhances utilization / reduces wait times.</p>
                <p>Speed on my RTX 3090 on average doubled compared to v0.3.2. On the Laptop with a throttled RTX 3050 I didn't see a noticeable differance (was already fully utilized on v0.3.2)</p>
                <p>You can find detailed speed performance numbers in the README.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-11" version="0.3.2">
            <description>
                <p>GUI: fix memory leak when opening another file if we're already previewing a video</p>
                <p>GUI: make sidebar scrollable if window height is not big enough to display everything</p>
                <p>CLI: reformat and group CLI arguments in --help output</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-09" version="0.3.1">
            <description>
                <p>GUI: Move mosaic restoration preview processing to its own thread to avoid blocking the UI</p>
                <p>GUI: Group common settings in sidebar</p>
                <p>GUI: Fix crash when video file has no audio track</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-08" version="0.3.0">
            <description>
                <p>GUI: Add mute/unmute audio functionality</p>
                <p>GUI: Implement keyboard shortcuts for common actions</p>
                <p>GUI: Persist configuration so that user preferences survive a restart</p>
                <p>GUI: Improve readability of config settings and tooltips</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-05" version="0.2.5">
            <description>
                <p>GUI: Adjustments and fixes for timeline playhead position updates</p>
                <p>GUI: set initial folder and file name based on file input</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-04" version="0.2.4">
            <description>
                <p>Fix GUI crash when video width is not divisible by 4</p>
                <p>Remove unused python dependencies and update dependencies to latest versions</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-12-02" version="0.2.3">
            <description>
                <p>Fix broken GUI export</p>
                <p>Improve support for files using various audio formats</p>
                <p>Fix handling overlapping detections that could result in flickering in certain scenes</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-11-09" version="0.2.2">
            <description>
                <p>Support light theme (use system default theme)</p>
                <p>Show cursor timeline position</p>
                <p>Support video files with variable frame rates</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-11-05" version="0.2.1">
            <description>
                <p>Small improvement to generic restoration model</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-11-02" version="0.2.0">
            <description>
                <p>New mosaic detection model</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release date="2024-10-29" version="0.1.0">
            <description>
                <p>Initial release of this project including all trained models</p>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
</component>
